I'm a writer and a journalist,
أنا كاتبة وصحفية،
and I'm also an insanely curious person,
وأنا أيضاً فضولية الى حد الجنون.
so in 22 years as a journalist,
إذاً خلال 22 عاماً كصحفية
I've learned how to do a lot of new things.
تعلمت أن أفعل الكثير من الأشياء الجديدة.
And three years ago, one of the things I learned how to do
وقبل ثلاث سنوات، أحد الأشياء التي تعلمت فعلها
was to become invisible.
كانت أن أصبح متخفية.
I became one of the working homeless.
أصبحت أحدى العاملات بلا مأوى.
I quit my job as a newspaper editor
تركت وظيفتي كمحررة للصحيفة
after my father died in February of that same year,
بعد أن توفي والدي في فبراير من تلك السنة،
and decided to travel.
وقررت التجوال.
His death hit me pretty hard.
وفاته كانت قاسية عليّ بشدة.
And there were a lot of things that I wanted to feel and deal with while I was doing that.
وكانت هناك الكثير من الأشياء التي رغبت في الشعور بها والتعامل معها بينما كنت أفعل ذلك.
I've camped my whole life. And I decided
حزمت كل حياتي. وقررت
that living in a van for a year to do this
أن أعيش في سيارة فان لمدة عام من أجل هذا
would be like one long camping trip.
ستكون مثل رحلة مخيّم طويلة.
So I packed my cat, my Rottweiler
لذا أخذت قطتي، وكلبي (فصيلة روت وايلر)،
and my camping gear into a 1975 Chevy van,
ومعدات التخييم خاصتي في سيارة فان ماركة تشيفي 1975،
and drove off into the sunset,
وأنطلقت نحو الغروب،
having fully failed to realize three critical things.
بعد أن فشلت تماما في تصديق ثلاثة أمور حرجة.
One: that society equates
أولاً: أن المجتمع يطابق بين الذين
living in a permanent structure, even a shack,
يعيشون في مساكن دائمة، حتى في الكوخ،
with having value as a person.
بقيمتك كإنسان.
Two: I failed to realize how quickly
ثانياً: فشلت في تصديق كيف أن التصور
the negative perceptions of other people
السلبي للأشخاص الآخرين بسرعة
can impact our reality, if we let it.
يمكن أن يؤثر على واقعنا ، إذا سمحنا بذلك.
Three: I failed to realize
ثالثاً: فشلت في تصديق
that homelessness is an attitude,
أن التشرد هو سلوك،
not a lifestyle.
وليس أسلوب حياة.
At first, living in the van was great.
في البداية، العيش في الفان كان عظيماً.
I showered in campgrounds. I ate out regularly.
لقد غسلت في المخيمات. كنت أتناول الطعام في الخارج بإستمرار.
And I had time to relax and to grieve.
وكان لدي وقت للإسترخاء وللحزن.
But then the anger and the depression about my father's death set in.
لكن حينما الغضب والإحباط حول رحيل والدي حدث.
My freelance job ended. And I had to get a full-time job
عملي الحُر أنتهى. وتوجب عليّ الحصول على عمل بدوام كامل.
to pay the bills.
لدفع الفواتير.
What had been a really mild spring
ما كان حقاً فصل ربيع معتدل
turned into a miserably hot summer.
تحوّل الى صيف ساخن بشدة.
And it became impossible to park anywhere --
وأصبح من الصعب ركن السيارة في كل مكان --
(Laughs)
(ضحكة)
-- without being very obvious
دون أن يكون واضحاً للغاية
that I had a cat and a dog with me, and it was really hot.
أن لديّ قطة وكلب معي، وكان الطقس حاراً جداً.
The cat came and went through an open window in the van.
القطة جاءت ودخلت عبر نافذة مفتوحة الى داخل الفان.
The doggy went into doggy day care.
الكلب ذهب في يوم العناية بالكلاب.
And I sweated.
وتصببت عرقاً.
Whenever I could, I used
كلما أستطعت، أستخدمت
employee showers in office buildings and truck stops.
حمامات الموظفين في بنايات الأعمال ومواقف السيارات.
Or I washed up in public rest rooms.
أو أستحممت في الحمامات العامة.
Nighttime temperatures in the van rarely dropped below 80 degrees Fahrenheit,
درجات الحرارة في الليل في الفان نادراً ما نقصت عن 80 درجة فهرنهايت،
making it difficult or impossible to sleep.
جاعلة من الصعب أو المستحيل النوم.
Food rotted in the heat.
المواد الغذائية فسدت بسبب الحرارة.
Ice in my ice chest melted within hours,
الثلج في الحافظة ذاب في غضون ساعات،
and it was pretty miserable.
وكان الأمر فظيع للغاية.
I couldn't afford to find an apartment,
لم أستطيع توفير ثمن الشقة،
or couldn't afford an apartment that would allow me
أو لم أستطيع الحصول على شقة ستتيح لي
to have the Rottweiler and the cat.
الإحتفاظ بالكلب والقطة.
And I refused to give them up,
ورفضت أن أتركهم.
so I stayed in the van.
وبقيت في سيارة الفان.
And when the heat made me too sick
وعندما تسببت الحرارة في مرضي بشدة
to walk the 50 feet to the public restroom
حتى أنني لا اقوى على السير 50 قدماً للحمام العام
outside my van at night,
خارج سيارتي في الليل،
I used a bucket and a trash bag as a toilet.
أستخدمت دلواً وكيس قمامة كمرحاض.
When winter weather set in, the temperatures dropped
وعندما حلّ الشتاء، إنخفضت درجات الحرارة
below freezing. And they stayed there.
تحت التجمد. وبقت على حالها.
And I faced a whole new set of challenges.
وواجهت مجموعة جديدة كلياً من التحديات.
I parked a different place every night
كنت أركن السيارة في مكان مختلف كل ليلة
so I would avoid being noticed and hassled by the police.
بحيث لا ألاحظ وأتجنب مضايقات الشرطة .
I didn't always succeed.
لم أكن أنجح دائماً.
But I felt out of control of my life.
لكن، شعرت بفقدان السيطرة على حياتي.
And I don't know when or how it happened,
ولا أعرف أين وكيف حصل ذلك،
but the speed at which I went
لكن السرعة التي مررت بها
from being a talented writer and journalist
من كوني كاتبة موهوبة وصحفية
to being a homeless woman, living in a van,
لأصبح إمرأة بلا مأوى، تعيش في سيارة فان،
took my breath away.
أخذت أنفاسي.
I hadn't changed. My I.Q. hadn't dropped.
لم أكن قد تغيرت. لم ينقص مستوى ذكائي.
My talent, my integrity, my values,
موهبتي، نزاهتي، قيمي،
everything about me remained the same.
كل شئ عني بقي كما هو.
But I had changed somehow.
لكني تغيرت بطريقة ما.
I spiraled deeper and deeper into a depression.
إنزلقت أعمق وأعمق في الإكتئاب.
And eventually someone referred me to a homeless health clinic.
وفي نهاية المطاف أشار لي أحدهم الى عيادة المشردين.
And I went. I hadn't bathed in three days.
وذهبت. لم أستحم لثلاثة أيام.
I was as smelly and as depressed as anyone in line.
كانت تنبعث مني روائح ومكتئبة كحال الجميع في الصف.
I just wasn't drunk or high.
فقط لم أكن سكرانة أو مسطولة.
And when several of the homeless men realized that,
وعندما عرف العديد من الرجال المشردين ذلك،
including a former university professor,
وضمنهم أستاذ جامعي أسبق،
they said, "You aren't homeless. Why are you really here?"
قالوا، " أنك لست مشردة. لماذا أنت هنا حقاً؟"
Other homeless people didn't see me as homeless,
بقية المشردين لا ينظرون لي كمشردة،
but I did.
خلافاً لنفسي.
Then the professor listened to my story and he said,
حينها أستمع البروفيسور لقصتي وقال،
"You have a job. You have hope.
"أنت لديك وظيفة. لديك أمل.
The real homeless don't have hope."
المشرد الحقيقي ليس لديه أمل."
A reaction to the medication the clinic gave me for my depression
رد فعل الدواء الذي أعطاني أياه الطبيب لإكتئابي
left me suicidal. And I remember thinking,
جعلني أرغب بالإنتحار. وأذكر أنني كنت أفكر،
"If I killed myself, no one would notice."
"إذا قتلت نفسي، لن يلاحظ أحد ذلك."
A friend told me, shortly after that,
أخبرتني صديقة، بعد ذلك بقليل،
that she had heard that Tim Russert,
أنها قد سمعت أن تيم روسيرت،
a nationally renowned journalist,
الصحفي المشهور قومياً
had been talking about me on national T.V.
كان يتحدث عني في التلفزيون القومي.
An essay I'd written about my father,
مقال كتبته عن أبي،
the year before he died, was in Tim's new book.
سنة قبل مماته، كان في كتاب تيم الجديد.
And he was doing the talk show circuit. And he was talking about my writing.
وكان يقدم حديث دائرة العرض. وكان يتحدث عن كتاباتي.
And when I realized that Tim Russert, former moderator of "Meet the Press,"
وعندما عرفت أن تيم روسيرت، المدير الأسبق للقاء الصحافة،
was talking about my writing,
كان يتحدث عن كتاباتي،
while I was living in a van in a Wal-Mart parking lot,
بينما كنت أعيش في الفان في موقف سيارات وول مارت،
I started laughing.
بدأت في الضحك.
You should too.
ينبغي أن تضحكوا أيضاً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I started laughing
بدأت في الضحك.
because it got to the point where,
لأنني وصلت الى النقطة حيث،
was I a writer, or was I a homeless woman?
هل أنا كاتبة، أم أنا إمرأة مشردة؟
So I went in the bookstore. And I found Tim's book.
لذا ذهبت الى متجر الكتب. ووجدت كتاب تيم.
And I stood there. And I reread my essay.
ووقفت هناك. وقرأت مقالي مرة أخرى.
And I cried.
وبكيت.
Because I was a writer.
لأنني كنت كاتبة.
I was a writer.
لقد كنت كاتبة.
Shortly after that I moved back to Tennessee.
بعد وقت قصير إنتقلت راجعة الى تينيسي.
I alternated between living in a van and couch surfing with friends.
وتناوبت العيش في الفان و التجوال مع الأصدقاء.
And I started writing again.
وبدأت الكتابة مجدداً.
By the summer of the following year I was a working journalist.
بحلول صيف العام المقبل كنت أعمل كصحفية.
I was winning awards. I was living in my own apartment.
كنت أفوز بالجوائز. كنت أعيش في شقتي التي أملكها.
I was no longer homeless.
لم أعد مشردة بعد ذلك.
And I was no longer invisible.
ولم أعد متخفية بعد ذلك.
Thousands of people work full and part-time jobs,
آلاف الناس يعملون بدوام كامل و جزئي،
and live in their cars.
ويعيشون في سياراتهم.
But society continues to stigmatize and criminalize
لكن المجتمع يواصل في تشويه السمعة وتجريم
living in your vehicle or on the streets.
العيش في سيارتك أو على الطرقات.
So the homeless, the working homeless, primarily remain invisible.
إذاً فالتشرد، العامل بلا مأوى، في الأساس يظل متخفياً.
But if you ever meet one,
لكن إذا حدث أن لاقيت شخص،
engage them, encourage them, and offer them hope.
أشركهم، شجعهم، وقدّم لهم الأمل.
The human spirit can overcome anything if it has hope.
الروح الإنسانية يمكنها التغلب على أي شئ إذا توفر لها الأمل.
And I'm not here to be the poster girl for the homeless.
وأنا لست هنا لأقوم بدعاية نسائية للمشردين.
I'm not here to encourage you to give money to the next panhandler you meet.
لست هنا لتشجيعكم لبذل المال للشحاذ المقبل الذي تلتقوه.
But I am here to tell you that, based on my experience,
لكني هنا لأخبركم بأنه ، بناء على خبرتي،
people are not where they live,
أن الناس ليسوا حيث يعيشون،
where they sleep,
حيث ينامون،
or what their life situation is at any given time.
أو حيث تكون حياتهم في أي وقت من الزمن.
Three years ago I was living in a van
قبل ثلاث سنوات كنت أعيش في الفان
in a Wal-Mart parking lot,
في موقف السيارات لوول مارت.
and today I'm speaking at TED.
واليوم أنا أتحدث في تيد.
Hope always, always finds a way. Thank you.
الأمل دائماً، دائماً، يجد طريقه. شكراً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)